Visual AIDS Artist Files
Visual AIDS Archive
- W Benjamin Incerti (1951–1993)
  Materials pertaining to W. Benjamin Incerti were donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Robert Sessions. They contain artist's biographies and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-2000.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/w.-benjamin-incerti
  - Box 27, Folder 1 (Box 27)
- Kenny Lee (Inkedkenny) (b. 1967)
  Kenny Lee (Inkedkenny) was born in 1967. His photography primarily centers gay culture and has appeared in various publications and has been exhibited in Canada.
  Kenny Lee (Inkedkenny) first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2009. They include a CD with images of art, a digital image list, and a periodical. These materials are dated 2009-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/inkedkenny
  - Box 27, Folder 2 (Box 27)
- JD Isaacs (b. 1953)
  JD Isaacs was born in 1953 in Dayton, Ohio. He received a BA in Communications from the University of Central Florida. His work includes sculpture and paintings, which have been exhibited in Georgia.
  JD Isaacs first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2010. They contain correspondence and a CD with images of art and accompanying image list. These materials are dated 2009-2010.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jd-isaacs
  - Box 27, Folder 4 (Box 27)
- Affrekka Jefferson (1950–2004)
  Affrekka Jefferson was born in 1950 in Brooklyn, New York. She received a BFA from the School of Visual Arts in New York. She worked primarily in printmaking, as well as oil painting. She was a lifetime member of the Art Students' League and her art is on permanent display at the Bedford-Stuyvesant Restoration in Brooklyn. She passed away in 2004.
  Affrekka Jefferson first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain an artist's statement, calendar submission materials, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, scans of artwork, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1980-2002.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/affrekka-jefferson
  - Box 28, Folder 3 (Box 28)
- Jerry the Marble Faun (b. 1955)
  Jerry the Marble Faun was born in 1955 in Brooklyn, New York. He is a Queens-based artist working primarily in stone and earthenware sculpture. He is known from his appearance in the 1975 documentary Grey Gardens, where he received his nickname. His work has been exhibited widely in New York and has been written about in numerous publications. In addition to sculpting, he has worked as a taxi driver, a performer, and a gardener.
  Materials pertaining to Jerry the Marble Faun include a publication dated 2015.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jerry-the-marble-faun
  - Box 69, Folder 5 (Box 69)
- David Jester (b. 1960)
  David Jester was born in 1960 and started drawing and painting at a young age. He received a BFA from Virginia Commonwealth University and an MFA from Rutgers University. He works in painting, primarily oil on wood.
  Materials pertaining to David Jester donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain grant application materials and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1995-1996.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-jester1
  - Box 28, Folder 4 (Box 28)
- Joe Jimenez (b. 1976)
  Joe Jimenez was born in 1976 in Arkansas Pass, Texas. He received a BA in English from Pomona College in California. He is a writer, photographer, editor, and altar artist. He is also a nationally recognized community organizer. His work has been published and exhibited widely.
  Joe Jimenez first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2002. They contain an artist's biography, an artist's statement, and CVs. These materials are dated 2002.
  - Box 28, Folder 6 (Box 28)
- Tim Jocelyn (1952–1986)
  Tim Jocelyn was born in 1952 in Ottawa, Canada. He graduated from Central Technical School in Toronto and became a central figure of the art scene there in the early 1980s. He first emerged as a clothing and accessory designer. His work has been exhibited widely in New York as well as across Canada. He passed away in 1986.
  Materials pertaining to Tim Jocelyn were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Sybil Goldstein. They contain exhibition announcements, an exhibition catalog, a CV, press releases, photocopies of press clippings, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1980-2002.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tim-jocelyn
  - Box 28, Folder 7 (Box 28)
- Shamar Johnson
  Shamar Johnson is a Brooklyn-based artist. His work includes illustration and plaster carving work.
  Materials pertaining to Shamar Johnson include Postcards from the Edge submission materials.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/mr-johnson
  - Box 28, Folder 11 (Box 28)
- Michael Johnstone (b. 1955)
  Michael Johnstone was born in 1955 in Edinburgh, Scotland. His artwork contains several mediums. He is primarily a photographer and also collaborates with his partner, David Faulk, to create art from recycled items and participate in colorful street spectacles.
  Materials pertaining to Michael Johnstone include postcards with images of artwork.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/michael-johnstone
  - Box 28, Folder 12 (Box 28)
- Constantine Jones (b. 1992)
  Constantine Jones was born in 1992 in Tennessee. They received an MFA from City College of New York where they teach creative writing. They are a poet and their work has been published in various outlets and has been performed and exhibited across New York City. They have published a novel and a collaborative chapbook.
  Constantine Jones first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2019. They contain correspondence and an event program. These materials are dated 2019.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/constantine-jones
  - Box 28, Folder 13 (Box 28)
- Darrell G. Jones (b. 1953)
  Darrell G. Jones was born in 1953 in Baltimore, Maryland. After a stint in the US Army, Jones moved to San Francisco and then New York. He studied at Pratt Institute, Fashion Institute of Technology, and the Art Students League. He works primarily in dawing and watercolor.
  Darrell G Jones first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials, exhibition announcements, ephemera, an artist's biography, an artist's statement, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1996-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/darrell-jones
  - Box 28, Folder 14 (Box 28)
- Frank Jump (b. 1960)
  Frank Jump was born in 1960 in Queens, New York. He received a BA in Music, Theatre and Film from Empire State College and an MS in education from Brooklyn College. He is a founding member of ACT UP and the author of the book Fading Ads of New York City, which documents vintage ads on buildings in New York.
  Frank Jump first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain postcards of art, exhibition announcements, artist's biographies, press clippings, exhibition materials, calendar submission materials, artist's statements, photographic prints, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, ephemera, correspondence, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1997-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/frank-jump
  - Box 29, Folder 1 (Box 29)
  - Box 29, Folder 2 (Box 29)
  - Box B, Folder 2 (Box B)
- Leslie Kaliades (1961–1999)
  Leslie Kaliades was born in 1961 in New York and educated at Rutgers University and the International Center for Photography in New York. Her photography was exhibited widely across the country and appeared on the cover of Body Positive. She passed away in 1999.
  Materials pertaining to Leslie Kaliades were first donated with the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Dorothy Kaliades. They contain CVs, exhibition materials, calendar submission materials, correspondence, exhibition catalogs, ephemera, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1989-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/leslie-kaliades
  - Box 29, Folder 3 (Box 29)
- Alexander Kargaltsev (b. 1985)
  Alexander Kargaltsev was born in 1985 and immigrated to the United States in 2010. He is very outspoken politically and his art is a reflection of that. His work is primarily in photography.
  Materials pertaining to Alexander Kargaltsev donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain Postcards from the Edge submission materials and a photograph. These materials are dated 2022-2023.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/alexander-kargaltsev
  - Box 29, Folder 4 (Box 29)
- John Carlos Keasler (b. 1949)
  John Carlos Keasler was born in 1949 in Texas and moved to California where he pursued painting and woodworking. He studied photography at San Diego City College as well as receiving a BA from North Texas State University. He served as the exhibition coordinator for San Diego non-profit organization AIDS Art Alive and has curated various other exhibitions as well as facilitating art therapy sessions. He lives in California.
  John Carlos Keasler first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2011. They contain a CD with images of art, a pamphlet of information about the artist, and a periodical. These materials are dated 2004-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/john-keasler
  - Box 29, Folder 5 (Box 29)
- Adrian Kellard (1959–1991)
  Adrian Kellard was born in 1959 in New Rochelle, New York. He studied at SUNY Purchase. His earliest works were woodcut prints which lead to his work with carved and painted wood blocks, often with religious themes. His work has been exhibited in New York as well as in a traveling museum exhibition. He passed away in 1991.
  Materials pertaining to Adrian Kellard donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain exhibition announcements, correspondence, and an excerpt from a press release. These materials are dated 1987-1990.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/adrian-kellard
  - Box 29, Folder 6 (Box 29)
- Sebron Kendrick (b. 1956)
  Sebron Kendrick was born in 1956 in East Chicago, Indiana. He studied at Illinois State University and excelled in both painting and printmaking, while also teaching classes. He received a Masters of Science with a concentration in fine arts also from ISU. He currently lives in Omaha, Nebraska.
  Sebron Kendrick first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2001. They contain CDs with images of artwork, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, an artist's biography, an artist's statement, CVs, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1980-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/sebron-kendrick1
  - Box 29, Folder 7 (Box 29)
- David King (b. 1962)
  David King was born in 1962 in Maine. He studied photography at Boston College and Boston Museum of Fine Arts School, and later received an MA in Anthropology from the California Institute of Integral Studies. His collages have been shown across Europe and the US. He lives in California with his husband.
  David King first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain CDs with images of artwork, exhibition announcements, ephemera, catalogs of artwork, CVs, artist's statements, correspondence, grant materials, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of artwork. These materials are dated 1992-2010.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-king
  - Box 29, Folder 11 (Box 29)
- Jochen Klein (1967–1997)
  Jochen Klein was born in 1967. He trained as a painter and studied classical painting at the Academy of Fine Arts in Munich. He turned away from classical painting and worked in conceptual art, joining the New York art collective Group Material. He moved to London in 1995 and continued painting, becoming known for his idyllic landscape scenes. He was also very actively socially and politically. He passed away in 1997.
  Materials pertaining to Jochen Klein donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain a press release and a gallery image list. These materials are dated 2017.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jochen-klein
  - Box 30, Folder 1 (Box 30)
- David Knudsvig (1947–1993)
  David Knudsvig was born in Stoughton, Wisconsin in 1947. He studied at St. Olaf's College, Los Angeles City College, and the University of Minnesota. His work used dense geometric patterning centered around the cteno, the Greek prefix for a five-pronged, comb-like for typically associated with zoological and aquatic creatures (for example, the comb jelly Ctenophora). Knudsvig's systems, ultimately, find the esoteric in the human; "five fingers," as the artist wrote in a diary entry, is "the pre- cursor to all ctenos." These figures have associations with counting, time, DNA and ancient text. His work was exhibited in New York. He passed away in 1993.
  Materials pertaining to David Knudsvig were donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain correspondence, a CD, a press release, a CV, an artist's statement, ephemera, an inventory list, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1988-1997.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/david-knudsvig
  - Box 30, Folder 3 (Box 30)
- Ken Kostovny (1965–1996)
  Ken Kostovny was born in 1965 in Los Angeles, California. Though he never had formal art training, he created many paintings and collages that were exhibited in San Francisco. He passed away in Colorado in 1996.
  Materials pertaining to Ken Kostovny were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997 by James Kovotny. They contain an artist's biography, ephemera, correspondence, copies of collage artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1985-1997.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/ken-kostovny
  - Box 30, Folder 4 (Box 30)
- Andre Brown Krauss (b. 1960)
  Andre Brown Krauss was born in 1960 in Albany, New York. He received a BA from Mohawk Valley College. His work is primarily painting, photography, and sculpture. It has been exhibited in New York and Florida.
  Andre Krauss first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2003. They contain CDs with images of art, correspondence, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1982-1992.
  - Box 30, Folder 6 (Box 30)
- Tseng Kwong Chi (1950–1990)
  Tseng Kwong Chi was born in 1950 in Hong Kong. He developed an artistic persona in the late 1970s as an "Ambiguous Ambassador" and traveled the world taking photos of himself at stereotypical tourist destinations. He settled in New York in 1979 and became best friend and official photographer to Keith Haring. His work has been exhibited internationally and is held in permanent collections, including the San Francisco Museum of Modern Art, New York's Guggenheim Museum, New York Public Library, New School in New York, Walker Art Center, and Los Angeles County Art Museum, among others. He passed away in 1990.
  Materials pertaining to Tseng Kwong Chi were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Muna Tseng. They contain photographic prints, exhibition announcements, exhibition programs, exhibition catalog, materials pertaining to art usage, an artist's biography, articles, correspondence, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1979-2008.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/tseng-kwong-chi
  - Box 61, Folder 3 (Box 61)
- Edwin Lacend (1960–2013)
  Edwin Lacend was born in 1960 in Puerto Rico and lived and worked in East Harlem. He studied at Parsons School of Design and worked with costume design as well as painting and multi-media art. His work was exhibited throughout New York. He passed away in 2013.
  Edwin Lacend first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998. They contain CDs with images of artwork, photographs of art, exhibition announcements, ephemera, CVs, correspondence, press clippings, artist's statements, calendar submission materials, grant submission materials, exhibition materials, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1996-2006.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/edwin-lacend
  - Box 30, Folder 8 (Box 30)
- Jeremy Landau (b. 1949)
  Jeremy Landau was born in 1949 in New Jersey. He received a BA and MA and was a health promotions professional for over twenty years, serving on President Clinton's Advisory Council. He was also a prolific fine arts and landscape photographer. His work has been exhibited across the US. He lives between New York and New Mexico.
  Jeremy Landau first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain a CD with images of art, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, CVs, correspondence, grant submission materials, artist's statements, and 35mm slide documentation of artwork. These materials are dated 1994-2001.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jeremy-g.-landau
  - Box 30, Folder 10 (Box 30)
- Morris Lane (b. 1954)
  Morris Lane was born in 1954 in Miami, Florida. He graduated from the Art Institute of New York with a degree in film. He has been a professional photographer for over 40 years, living and working in New York. He has also studied in Europe and photographed various celebrities.
  Morris Lane first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2011. They contain a CV, an artist's statement, images of the artist, and image lists. These materials are dated 1982-2011.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/morris-lane
  - Box 30, Folder 11 (Box 30)
- John Larabee (1954–1989)
  John Larabee was born in 1954 in Topeka, Kansas. He studied painting at the Massachusetts College of Art and the Boston Museum School. His work was exhibited in Provincetown, Boston, and Washington DC during his lifetime. He passed away in 1989 in Boston, Massachusetts.
  Materials pertaining to John Larabee were first donated to the Visual AIDS archive in 1998 by Alan Dinsfriend. They contain a CV, an artist's statement, an artist's biography, correspondence, an exhibition catalog, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1987-2003.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/john-larabee
  - Box 30, Folder 12 (Box 30)
- John Lathram (b. 1962)
  John Lathram was born in 1962 in Lexington, Kentucky. He received both a BFA and an MFA in Art and Technology from Ohio State University. He is a mixed media artist whose work incorporates digital photography, video, robotics, and computer software. His work has been exhibited in New York and Ohio.
  John Lathram first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1999. They contain a CD with images of art, CVs, biographies, press clippings, correspondence, grant submission materials, photographs of artwork, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1995-2011.
  - Box 30, Folder 13 (Box 30)
- John Laub (1947–2005)
  John Laub was born in 1947 in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. He studied art in Ohio before returning to Philadelphia to pursue graphic design. He switched to painting and immersed himself in the Philadelphia art community. He also did community work with GMHC in New York and spent time in the Fire Island Pines. He exhibited work Philadelphia, DC, San Francisco, and New York. He passed away in 2005.
  Materials pertaining to John Laub donated to the Visual AIDS archive include artwork on postcards, correspondence, exhibition announcements, exhibition catalogs, photographic documentation of art, a photographic print, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1991-2012.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/john-laub
  - Box 31, Folder 1 (Box 31)
- David Lee
  David Lee is a New York-based artist. His work is primarily in pastel and acrylic on canvas.
  David Lee first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain photographs of the artist, an image list, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1990-1998.
  - Box 31, Folder 2 (Box 31)
- Michael Lee (b. 1956)
  Michael Lee was born in 1956 in Norwich, Connecticut. After high school he moved to New York City and then Paris before returning to New York. There he worked at Bloomingdale's Visual Design Studio. His artwork has been featured in various magazines, and exhibitions in New York.
  Michael Lee first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain an exhibition announcement, an artist's biography, correspondence, an artist's statement, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image list. These materials are dated 1991-2001.
  - Box 31, Folder 3 (Box 31)
- Jonathan Leiter (b. 1959)
  Jonathan Leiter was born in 1959 in Uniontown, Pennsylvania. He grew up in the New York area and received a BA in theater design from Rutgers University where he also studied painting and performance art. He has performed under the name Reuben Sandwich since 1980 in many performance spaces around New York. His visual artwork includes painting, sculpture, collage, and mixed media.
  Jonathan Leiter first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 1997. They contain exhibition announcements, images of artwork, CVs, Postcards from the Edge submission materials, a periodical, and 35mm slide documentation of art. These materials are dated 1993-2013.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/jonathan-leiter
  - Box 31, Folder 4 (Box 31)
- Nancer Lemoins (b. 1956)
  Nancer Lemoins was born in 1956 in St Louis, Missouri. She studied painting and printmaking at Evergreen State College in Olympia, Washington and New College of San Francisco. She lived and worked in San Francisco and has exhibited her art widely in California.
  Nancer Lemoins first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2000. They contain photographs of artwork, stickers of artwork, exhibition announcements, ephemera, CDs with images of artwork, CVs, an artist's statement, calendar submission materials, press clippings, correspondence, periodicals, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 1999-2014.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/nancer-lemoins
  - Box 31, Folder 5 (Box 31)
  - Box 31, Folder 6 (Box 31)
- Jose Leonilson (1957–1993)
  Jose Leonilson Bezerra Dias was born in 1957 in Brazil. He studied at the Escola Pan-Americana de Arte and the Fundação Armando Alvares Penteado (FAAP) in São Paulo. He emerged as a seminal figure of the Brazilian contemporary art world during the 1980s. He traveled extensively and had paintings, drawings, and installations exhibited in France, Germany, Italy, and Spain. After his HIV diagnosis he began to work on intimate embroideries. His art remains in public and private collections internationally. He passed away in 1993.
  Materials pertaining to Jose Leonilson donated to the Visual AIDS archive contain an exhibition announcement. This materials is dated 2018.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/leonilson
  - Box 69, Folder 12 (Box 69)
- Eric Lerner (1961–2021)
  Eric Lerner was born in 1961 in Patterson, New Jersey. He received a BA in english from the University of Maryland. He is self-taught in art and his work consists of mixed media, acrylic, and digital manipulation. His work has been exhibited in New York and Maryland. He passed away in 2021.
  Eric Lerner first donated materials to the Visual AIDS archive in 2007. They contain CDs with images of art, an artist's statement, a CV, an interview, correspondence, calendars, and 35mm slide documentation of art with accompanying image lists. These materials are dated 2003-2008.
  https://visualaids.org/artists/eric-lerner
  - Box 31, Folder 8 (Box 31)
- John Lesnick (1953–2003)